You got 20 minutes.
♪ To get inside my mind
Is this what you wanted
♪ Get me all turned around
Tell me baby
Hello?
No! No!
What's going on in there?
John own memories are intruding.
He's having a seizure.
Marjorie! Get in there! Now!
Senator Rockford has been
identified as the target...
of an FBI investigation, involving
embezzlement and accusations of blackmail.
Senator!
I whole heartedly and emphatically deny any
and all allegations leveled against me.
His attorney has secured the
services of Mindscape...
the world's top memory
detective agency...
to gather information about his past and
help the FBI with the investigation.
Memory detectives, as
they're commonly known...
have experienced a resurgence
in recent years...
thanks to the growing number of cases
solved using the remote viewing technique.
In the early 70 s, the
Defense Intelligence Agency
began conducting top secret experiments
with people with psychic abilities
to help gather intelligence
for modern warfare.
They came across a
group of ESP's...
that had the ability to
access people's memories
and observe them as they were experienced
in the past by the subjects.
The findings of memory detectives do
not yet carry the same weight...
as DNA evidence in court...
but currently prove more
reliable than polygraph tests.
They say, remote viewing is nothing
more than an elaborate scam...
but the reality is, remote viewers
have been solving cases...
that have been cold for years.
Most recently, the murder of
child actress Kate Henderson...
was solved by memory
detective John Washington.
Shit.
Hello?
- Ah, hello!
- Good Morning!
I'm calling about
the house for sale.
No... no... we're not selling
the house anymore, I'm sorry.
Well... the agency listing says
it's still active.
Yeah, I know it's still listed at the
agency, but we're not selling it, okay?
Mr. Washington's own
traumatic memories...
were blending in with
his clients memories...
which impaired his ability
to focus during sessions.
And thank you.
Now it seems, Senator Rockford is betting
his political career on Mindscape...
the prime memory detective
agency in the world.
The rumors that the Mindscape program
is dangerous, are unfounded.
John is here.
John... how are you?
I'm great.
You're still taking the medication?
No, I'm done with all that.
Well, you're lucky
the stroke was mild.
You could be relearning
your abc's right now.
That's true.
Yes?
Uh... I'm good.
Nice.
You met anybody recently?
You know, John, maybe it's time
to get back in the running.
I'm not there yet.
It's been two years.
You should move on from
what happened to your wife.
And you know it wasn't your fault.
Yeah, well...
Oh, shit! Shit! Sorry.
Ah, don't worry about it.
Don't worry!
I'm so sorry.
Don't worry about it.
I'm sorry.
Here... sit down!
Sorry.
I heard Senator Rockford on... TV...
talking about the possibility
of hiring a memory detective.
Oh, yeah, yeah. Peter Lundgren
is already working on the case.
Rockford hired him.
Lundgren?
C'mon! I was better than him
on my worst day!
Yeah, but gifts like
yours need to be used.
You've been out of
the game for months.
And Lundgrens' success nowadays
is close to 100 percent.
What's the matter?
To be honest, I'm
running out of money.
You still have the beach house?
Yeah.
Go ahead. Sell it.
I'm not ready to sell it yet.
What I was wondering was whether I
could do something for Mindscape.
As it happens, I, uh...
I might have something you're
right for, perfect actually.
Her name is Anna.
Oh, you're kidding.
Forget about the name, right?
She used to be my patient
when she was little.
Very special girl...
she's a teenager now, but I don't
think a... a doctor can help.
Maybe a viewer can.
Well, what's her problem?
She's on a hunger strike.
All you have to do is get her to eat.
Just tell the parents to
hide the fashion magazines.
John...
You know, it could be a quick one for you,
if you didn't wanna sell the beach house.
Hi John, I'm so happy
you're back in the saddle.
Anna's still refusing to eat,
trying to pressure them...
into letting her out of the house.
She's very fragile,
so tread carefully.
Try to find a trauma for her
therapist to work on... bye.
Thank you so much for
working on Anna's case.
I'm Michelle.
John.
And this is Anna's
stepfather, Robert.
Sebastian speaks
very highly of you.
Even as a baby, Anna was unusual.
She didn't smile when you smiled at
her, but she didn't cry much, either.
I would say she was unusually
focused for a child, always calm.
She looked at things as if she
already knew what they were.
Later, of course, we took her to a specialist,
and her IQ score came back off the charts.
When was the last time she ate?
She stopped eating one week ago.
She's taking vitamins and
drinking water, but nothing else.
In my opinion, she should be... in a
place that can provide the proper care.
I'm sure Anna can get better here.
Mr. Washington, ah... as I'm
sure you can appreciate...
this is a matter that
requires great discretion.
I will need you to sign a
non-disclosure contract...
that anything revealed in Anna's memories can't
be disseminated beyond Michelle and myself.
Of course.
Anna is so special, she's
so many talents, she's...
Gifted.
Yes, gifted.
I think there are
better words for it.
Such as?
I would say haunted.
What happened to
Anna's real father?
He died... when I was pregnant.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Does Anna get along with Robert?
Not well, lately... but he's
tried to do his best for her.
I see.
This way.
Is there any specific reason
why Anna is refusing to eat?
She wants to go back to school,
but that's impossible.
I'm sure Sebastian told you
about her cutting herself.
We've had to remove all sharp
objects from her room.
We need to protect her.
From what?
To protect her, from herself.
Sweetie. This is John...
the gentleman I told you
was coming to visit.
Aren't you late for
your AA meeting, Mom?
Can I have a seat?
Do you mind?
We won't guess the next one for sure,
so go ahead, make yourself comfortable.
That's quite the party
trick you have there.
What's the metronome for?
I like the rhythm when I draw.
It's soothing.
Better?
Much.
Anna, you know what catabolysis is?
If you don't eat, your
organs are gonna fail.
John, do you know what "prana" is?
It's sanskrit, it means vital life.
There are Yogis in
India who rarely eat.
They get all their energy or
"prana" from the air and the sun.
Is that what you're doing?
Are you a doctor?
No, but I do have to ask
you some questions.
I would like you to tell me
what expression you see.
What am I getting in exchange for
making you earn some of Robert's money?
Well, you might get to
know yourself better.
What do you see?
Malice.
I'm kidding.
He's expressing happiness,
maybe even affection.
What about this guy?
That guy's pissed off.
Uh-huh.
What about her?
I think her husband's out late,
and she's wondering where he is.
She's worried he's with someone else, but
she's also glad to have the down time...
'cause he's a loser.
Right.
I'm gonna tell you a story...
and then I'm gonna ask you
a question. Okay?
There's this girl about your
age at her mother's funeral.
At the funeral, she sees this
guy she's never seen before.
She gets to meet him, briefly.
And she thinks he's amazing.
He's everything she's ever wanted.
She falls in love with
him, right there and then.
But, in the crowds at the
funeral, she gets separated...
from him before she has a
chance to ask for his number.
And two days later... this
girl... kills her own sister.
What's her motive for
killing her sister?
Her motive is she wants
to meet the guy again.
Did I get it right?
Oh, there's no right answer.
Depends on what you're looking for.
Why is that?
You're testing me to see if
I think like a sociopath.
Sociopaths sometimes have trouble
reading facial expressions.
With the second test, I gave you
the answer you were looking for...
but, the fact is, that
story has a flawed set up.
The more logical outcome would be
for the girl to kill her father.
Why?
If the girl didn't know the man,
it's unlikely her sister would.
And it was her mother's funeral
where she met this guy...
so it would make more sense
for her to kill her father.
There would be a higher
probability that the...
the mystery stud would
attend her father's funeral.
That's probably true.
I'm not a sociopath, just smart
enough to think like one.
Can I see what you're drawing?
If you're not a doctor,
then what are you?
I take people to their memories.
She's monitored all the time?
24-7.
If you need anything while you're here, you
can ask me or Ralph, we both watch Anna.
I'm John.
Oh, I'm Judith... this is my cell.
Call me, if you can't
make a session.
I will.
You were right about
her, she's smart.
Special kid, lots of problems.
What do you think are
the underlying issues?
Depression, bipolar disorder
with deep-seeded narcissism.
I'm gonna need her full file to
know what memories to target.
Parents don't want full disclosure.
What? Why? I signed an agreement!
She's been in and out of boarding
schools, involved in some incidents...
but you don't need
to get into that.
Just let her take
the lead, you know?
I mean... a few memories where
the parents screw up.
As you know, usually, the dramatic experience
of actually going back into memories...
affects people, gives them perspective
on their present lives...
to stop overeating, stop
smoking... whatever.
Make her eat. Simple case.
Will I know I'm in a memory?
It should feel like it's
happening for the first time...
but it'll be different
from the original event.
Because your unconscious mind will
know that you've been there before.
Also...
me being there makes it different.
The equipment is useful
to record the session.
I will be watching you
for the whole time.
If anything happens, I can bring
you back, right away. Okay?
Now, you may see me in the distance,
but you won't know that it's me.
If I'm next to you, you won't
be able to see me at all...
unless I call you back.
Understand?
Yes.
Please put these in your ears.
They conceal a tone,
hidden in white noise.
It enables the brain to
go into a theta state.
Can we use my metronome as well?
Uh... sure.
Where are we going?
Focus on your first memory.
The further back we
can go, the better.
Give me your hands.
Relax.
Think about that first memory.
At first, your memories will
jump around, but that's okay.
When you're ready...
close your eyes.
Let's begin...
now.
I like you being here with us...
We all know you like girls.
She's just a girl for god sakes!
We have a responsibility!
Let me out!
She needs to be in an institution!
She's my daughter!
This old man, he played three.
He played knick-knack on my knee.
With a knick-knack paddy whack...
give a dog a bone...
this old man came rolling home.
What game are you playing, honey?
Can I play with you?
You have to be quiet.
What are you up to?
Mommy's not feeling well today.
You can't do that!
You can't just...
We have to think about Anna.
Anna is the focus of the attention.
Don't you think I'm
thinking about her?
We have a responsibility!
We are not the right people!
This is not the place
for her, Michelle!
Come with me, young lady! Dad!
Let me down!
I'll let you out when you realize
that spying on people is wrong.
For god's sakes, She's only a girl!
She's different, Michelle.
She's not like other children, she
needs to be in an institution.
Well, why isn't it here, then?
Because I put it in here.
She's my daughter.
She tried to stab you,
for Christ's sakes!
Mom!
And coming back... now.
Ow.
Are you okay?
You were there?
I was right next to you.
Spooky.
Can we do more?
Next time.
Self-involved, emotionally stunted retards
is what one hopes for in parents.
Did you see the letter opener?
I did.
Maybe my stepdad is the one you should
be testing for personality disorders.
Is he why you're on
a hunger strike?
So you married?
I was.
What was her name?
Same as yours.
I like her already.
Show me a picture.
I don't carry one anymore.
C'mon, John.
A guy like you always has
a picture in his wallet.
I'll show you a picture...
if you agree to eat something.
You wanna see her?
It's up to you.
Robert desperately
wants to put me away.
And something like LSD in my
food would make me act crazy.
Well then, let's flip out together.
If I start hallucinating,
you'll demand a drug test...
before they lock me away
in a padded room, right?
I swear.
C mon, let's eat!
She's pretty.
Eat slowly so you don't
make yourself sick.
Why do you wanna see this
antique letter opener?
I like to confirm memories,
just to be sure.
I cut her accidentally.
It's always haunted me.
Is your husband here?
Mm-hm.
Can I talk to you both?
Why?
Anna just started to eat.
So, will I see you at
7:00 to celebrate?
Okay, shall I pick you up then?
Sure, why not?
But only one drink.
So you like being a nurse?
I like helping people.
You take your job
quite seriously, huh?
Well, if you can't do what you love, then
at least make sure you love what you do.
Isn't that what they say?
They do say that, that
is absolutely true.
I think you're doing a
great job with Anna.
Thank you for your confidence.
Sometimes I don't think I'm
gonna be able to help her.
Why?
My wife and I had a baby boy...
who died a few months
after he was born.
My wife kept wanting to go back to the
time when he was still alive, and...
eventually the time came when...
she wasn't happy unless
she was in the memory.
She became obsessed.
So, I refused to take her
to the past anymore.
She... spiraled downward, she...
became depressed and I lost her.
I couldn't help her.
I tried to keep her in the house,
but you can't lock someone up...
just because of your own fears.
I had a great time.
Me, too.
I hope I didn't talk too much.
Oh, you did...
but I liked it.
Thank you.
So, you're not even gonna try
to come up, so I can say no?
Uh...
I gotta go.
Safe home.
It's not your fault, John!
I'm telling you, Sebastian,
I saw her last night.
That's impossible.
She's under lock and key,
never allowed to leave her room.
I know, but I... I know what I saw.
Do you, John?
Is everything all right?
Everything's fine.
We may have one, because
there are blind spots.
What's happened?
Anna pushed Judith down the stairs.
Judith is in the hospital
with multiple fractures.
Look at this.
Oh, my god!
There's no other angle at
the top of the stairs?
Blind spot.
On Monday, Anna will be
confined to an institution...
that can properly
address her needs.
Fortunately, as a family friend, Judith
will not be pressing any charges.
I didn't do it, John.
Then why would Judith say you did?
Judith always sneaks
back in late at night.
Mom's knocked-out on sleeping pills,
and that's when they have sex.
Who? Robert and Judith?
He always sleeps with the good
looking help. Just ask Jaime.
I mean, you saw what she was doing
with Robert in the library.
I don't believe you.
When she first came here,
Judith had tried to make friends with me.
And she was all like,
"I have no luck with men".
Well, my stepfather moved right in.
You know, maybe... maybe they
had a fight, it got violent...
and now they're trying to cover it
up by blaming it on the sick girl.
Or maybe Robert just
cold-bloodedly pushed her, okay?
This is exactly the kind of thing
he's been hoping for to lock me up.
Oh, c'mon, Anna.
Open your eyes, John!
My mother's family is one
of the richest in America.
And Robert's on an allowance.
If I die, the money goes to a
charitable trust and he gets zilch.
But if I'm committed...
I get the money,
but I have no rights.
Robert controls every penny.
And I'm sure Judith knows this.
Maybe he was afraid that she was gonna tell
you and that you'd find out his secret plans.
And I'm sure he told you, only moments ago,
that they send me to an institution on Monday.
Am I right?
Please, John, you have to help
me prove that I'm innocent.
You're the only person
they're gonna trust.
I... I can't get send away to a
mental institution.
I won't survive that.
I know... I know I'm different,
not like other girls...
but doesn't mean I'm a murderer.
I don't even... I don't even think of doing
half the things they're accusing me of!
Please, John!
Help me figure out what the
hell's going on with me.
I mean, you're all I have.
John.
How do you feel?
Pretty out of it.
Judith, did you see...
Anna push you down the stairs?
Are you here for Anna or for me?
I'm here for you.
But I need to know what happened.
I know I went to
bring her some food.
I thought I locked the door.
Why don't you go to my memory?
Ah... doesn't work like that.
How do you know it wasn't Robert?
Robert?
Judith, I know.
Know what?
I know about you and Robert.
Did he hit on me?
Whatever, doesn't matter.
There's nothing going on
between me and Robert.
Look, I...
I hope you get better soon.
I can't believe that
Anna would hurt Judith.
Can you help my daughter, John?
I believe I can, Mrs. Greene.
I can take her to her traumatic memories,
help her understand her behavior.
And I wanna find out the truth.
My husband wants to send her to
a professional care facility.
I don't want that, but he's already
paid the registration fee...
and they're expecting
her in a week.
As soon as I see that file, I'll
know what I should be looking for.
I'll have Sebastian's assistant
send it to you right away.
Sebastian has it?
You'll see why the family didn't
want you to see the file.
It's strong stuff, John.
You said this was a simple case.
And it should have been, John.
Maybe you're not
ready to come back.
Look... they're gonna put Anna
in an institution.
If you'd sent me the file earlier,
maybe I could have prevented all this.
Are you sure you want to
continue with the case?
I'm Anna's best hope right now.
I'll call you in a couple of days.
Do you know why you're here, Anna?
That's pretty obvious.
For just one day, can we talk
about something other than me?
What made you try to kill yourself?
Red...
it's such a dark, rich color.
Particular shade,
it's hard to come by.
Blood... it's red.
It's kind of beautiful.
Can you tell me about your
relationship with your parents?
My mother's trying harder, I suppose,
but it's still pretty pathetic.
Her heart's like... one of those fancy
ice sculptures they have at parties.
Do you really want to know the answer?
Please.
It's my parents who
are crazy... not me.
Did you have feelings for your teacher?
Mr. Tatum?
That school was depressing.
He was nice.
Did he take pictures of you?
Would you mind if I
take a picture of you?
Yes.
What kind of pictures?
Artistic photos.
It was like a Jackson
Pollock painting...
where the blood sprayed
across the floor.
I can still see the exact
pattern when I close my eyes.
Do you want to die, Anna?
Don't we all die in the end?
It's kind of a freedom.
There are other ways to be free.
Not if you're not
allowed to have it.
Then what do you do?
Will you lift your chin a bit?
How do you feel when you draw?
Like the whole world disappears.
Like nothing else matters.
All right, finished.
Can I see it?
Not yet.
Can I have your bag?
Promise me you'll look
at it when you get home?
I promise.
Are we even now?
Can we start the session?
Yeah, we can.
Mousey?
It's extremely dangerous.
My real name is Megan Scanlon.
Had sex with your teacher?
Who you raping, bitch?
Hi, I'm Mousey.
Mousey?
That's really your name?
It's what the people here call me.
My real name is
Megan, Megan Scanlon.
So Susan Merricks your roommate.
What's she really like?
I heard she was training for the
Olympics, had a nervous breakdown...
beat up a horse or something.
Oh, great!
Frigid and Mousey are here.
Look, just because I've been
assigned to watch over you...
doesn't mean you have to be in
the room all the time, Frigid.
Name's Anna.
Capital A, N, N, A.
Leave.
Now.
Or maybe the reason you won't go is
because you wanna watch me changing.
Right, Frigid?
What are you doing?
No! No! No! Please don't!
No! No! No! Stop!
Cameras will be locked up, and can only
be signed out for a day at a time.
The chemicals you will be
using could be harmful...
and any misuses, however slight,
will end your art privileges.
Now, who here has experience
with the art of photography?
Anna.
Someone broke into the principal's
house and stole all the alcohol.
Do you know who might
have done this?
House Mother, you're
talking to someone...
who takes the harmful effects
of alcohol very seriously.
Drinking is the
Devil's calling card.
Hey, Anna, look.
I'm so, so sorry about
the closet. I...
Oh, don't worry about it.
Some friends are coming over to tea
tomorrow. Do you want to join us?
Can Megan come?
What, Mousey? She's such a retard.
Yeah, she is.
Do you copy your roses from
the rose bushes out there?
Roses don't grow during the winter.
Sometimes we remember things the way we want
to, rather than the way they really were.
I didn't do anything to those girls,
if that's what you're implying.
False memories can have a... a
rushed feeling to them...
a lack of detail.
The windows won't have views or
none of the clocks will work.
Well, if you ever find me, ah,
particularly attractive in a memory...
it's probably because
I'm making it up, too.
I wouldn't picture myself having a bad
skin day if I knew you'd be around.
Hey, I'm not kidding, okay?
I can accept we don't exactly
know what we're looking for...
but your memories have to be real!
You have to be very careful!
Has something told you
I've been making them up?
Yeah, I saw a clock on the wall,
the hands weren't moving.
The one in the dorm hallway, right?
Yeah.
That one never worked.
We used to call our gym teacher, Mr. Pierce
"The Clock", because he didn't work, either.
You never leave the house, right?
Not anymore.
You've got 20 minutes.
Mr. Ortega?
So, what are you?
Some kind of therapist?
Do you know what a
memory detective is?
Somebody who takes
rich people's money.
Well, that's me.
Has Anna's family hired you to
find out if she has a soul?
I'm just here to
find out the truth.
That family is a nightmare.
You dig too deep,
better watch your step.
You're lucky you didn't get 20
years for seducing a minor.
I'm not saying I wasn't at
fault, but that girl...
that girl was everywhere I
turned... flirting...
finding ways to get us alone.
I've lost everything.
My job, my fiance, my freedom...
my entire fucking
life, because of her.
Anna's family throws money
around like confetti.
They can get to anybody.
Cops, district attorneys...
They've covered up all the
bad stuff Anna's done.
Then, had me thrown in here
for something I didn't do.
I'm sure that they even covered
it up when she tried to kill...
those three girls at
school that same year.
Anna blamed it all on
another girl, Mousey...
but no one could find
out who she was.
Not even Susan Merrick s family
was able to take Anna to court.
I'd love that family to finally
get what's coming to them.
Susan Merrick?
My name is John Washington. Can I ask
you a few questions about Anna Greene?
Are you a cop?
No, I'm not a cop, Ms. Merrick.
What? Has she died or something?
No... not at all.
I just want to find out what happened, what
really happened at the Whitten Academy.
You think Anna was responsible.
Of course, she was a total psycho.
There were a lot of other girls there
with problems. Could have been anyone.
I got on with everyone.
Did you have a girl named
Mousey at your school?
No... I don't think so.
Now, I'm sorry, but I have to go.
Miss Merrick, I know what
you've been through.
I know it must have
been extremely painful.
I really need your help.
Do you have any specific memory
of Anna you think I should know?
Yeah... sure I do.
Anna seriously has balls. She was like
"drinking is the Devil's calling card".
It was awesome.
Hey, Anna, do you want a cup?
No, thanks.
You sure?
Yeah.
I like you being here with us.
And coming back... now.
You saw Mousey, right? She did it.
So you didn't poison those girls?
Of course, not.
Your prints were all over the teapot.
Because I picked it up once or twice.
And why would I wipe the poison clean,
but leave my prints on the teapot?
Not to mention hiding the
poison under my bed.
Maybe you're too smart
for your own good.
If you'd wiped the pot,
that would point to you.
Maybe you just didn't have
time to hide the poison.
It was Megan, John.
Why didn't you go to the cops?
What, and tell them that Megan was obsessed
and that she smirked at me as I was led away?
Why not?
You're forgetting what it's
like to be a teenager.
Adults telling you what to do, having opinion
about what you say, before you even say it.
There's no Mousey, Anna.
What?
What are you talking about?
There's no Megan at the school.
Oh, you don't believe me?
Do you blame me?
Megan transferred in during the second
semester and left right after I got expelled.
You know, who the hell
do you think I am?
Please tell me, John!
What... what, you think
I'm some psychopath?
What? This is the second day in
a row you've called me a liar!
I want to know why you're
suddenly turning on me!
Here! My yearbook!
Asshole.
You won't mind if I hang on
to this for a couple of days?
Sleep with it under your
pillow, for all I care.
We don't have much time.
I want you to think about all the key
moments in your life by tomorrow.
Can you do that for me?
Fine.
John...
John, Why don't you help me?
Why don't you wanna help me?
Mom!
This old man, he played three.
He played knick-knack on my knee.
With a knick-knack paddy whack...
give a dog a bone, this old...
Who's there?
Anna?
Anna!
Hello?
Hey!
Wait!
Is there somewhere
I can freshen up?
There's a bathroom just down
that corridor on your left.
Oh, thank you.
What are you doing in here?
Maybe I'm looking for the
guy from last night.
You know, Mr. Greene, it really isn't
necessary to have me followed.
I had you extensively looked
into before you were hired.
I don't have anyone
following you now.
And now, if you'd be so kind, your
work in this house is upstairs.
Very nice, Anna.
Not just yet.
Glad you're back from zombie land.
You okay, want some water?
Aren't they great?
Better than what you had before.
How did you do that?
I just downloaded it.
No, how did you leave
me alone in the memory?
I don't know.
Suddenly I was back here, and our hands
were separated, but you were still under.
I wasn't sure what to do.
You looked cute while
you were sleeping.
Anna, do you know
what transference is?
I do.
Then you'll know it's
perfectly natural to...
To what? Have strong feelings
for your therapist?
I just simply said I liked
watching you sleep.
Your teacher was a lot older
than you, he took advantage.
He was encouraging... that
place was so depressing.
What about the photos?
He said they were for art, and
at first they were artistic.
You okay? You don't look too good.
I'm having trouble
staying grounded.
Side-effects from the sessions?
Hallucinations?
Yeah... terrible headaches. I
can't sleep... nightmares.
Plus the guy they've hired to follow me...
he's... he is everywhere I go.
Maybe events have made this case far bigger
than you were ready for when you started.
Maybe we should ask
Lundgren to take over.
No! No way, no.
I can handle it.
Did you ever treat
Anna at their house?
No.
Did you ever have reason to
suspect abuse within the family?
Nothing with the stepfather?
Highly unlikely. I mean, look,
Robert's a prominent guy.
I wouldn't go down that
road based on a hunch.
Tom Ortega told me Anna's
parents set him up for...
You went to see Tom Ortega?
That lowlife took dirty
pictures of Anna.
You should be focusing on the sessions,
not investigating in the real world.
You need to be objective, John.
There is something going on
there behind the scenes...
I need to find out what it is.
You need to consider that this job
is too big and too complex...
and that you are becoming
too personally involved.
Whatever it is, I'm gonna
find out the truth.
Do you know where you want to go?
I went through all the photos and
one of them made me feel something.
Don't tell me.
Don't corrupt the
memory, just go there.
When you're ready, close your eyes.
Let's begin... now.
My parents brought him to me.
Who?
I don't remember his name.
This old man, he played three.
He played knick-knack on my knee.
With a knick-knack paddy whack,
give a dog a bone.
This old man came rolling home.
What are you doing
over there, Anna?
Why don't you come here...
next to me.
Come here, sweetheart.
Don't be afraid.
I won't hurt you.
And coming back... now!
Anna?
Anna, can you hear me?
You're okay, you fainted.
What happened?
Can you get some water. She's okay.
Yeah, sure.
Take this.
What is it?
It's a bit of one of your mom's
sedatives. It'll help you sleep.
So, what happens now?
Now... you get better.
This is the key to the house my
parents lived in when I was born.
I always felt safe there.
So many times in my life
people have been unkind.
I can't thank you enough, John.
Will you keep this
with you at all times?
If I know you have it, then at least I
know that there's someone out there...
who's on my side.
I might not be going
to an institution...
but I still feel trapped.
Sure.
Hey! Hey!
John? What are you doing here? You should
have called, I've got dinner guests.
Why Sebastian?
Christ! She was just a child.
What's going on?
You've been drinking?
These were in Anna's memories.
Have you been in my office?
I've seen you with her, in the
library, in one of the memories.
Oh, I might have been
there once, I forgot!
What's this all about?
You said you never treated her at
the house, but you were there!
Are you trying to say I
did something to her?
Think this through, John.
Why would I ask you to take on a
case, if I was guilty of something?
Think about what it is
you're accusing me of...
then, think about who
it is you're accusing.
They wanted to hire Peter Lundgren.
You brought me in, because I
was down, and I was weak...
and I was easy to manipulate.
Right?
And you wouldn't let me see that
file until you absolutely had to.
You said they didn't want me to see
it, but you had it the whole time!
I never told you I
didn't have the file!
I said the family wanted privacy.
What about the other day? Ah?
You wanted me to drop the case.
I said that because...
Now... I know what you didn't
want me to find out.
I said that because I
was worried about you!
Oh, c'mon, John!
You've been drinking alone.
Having hallucinations for days!
You're ignoring me
again, Uncle Sebastian
Hi, sweetheart.
Sorry. John...
Don't you ever go near
Anna again! You hear me?
John!
Due to Anna's early
overt sexualization...
she has a need for control...
which manifests itself in
a variety of disorders.
She has... significant
difficulty...
in forming and maintaining long-term
relationships with others.
Basically, she has developed
a protective shell...
Do you like it?
Which keeps out the pain...
and keeps out everything else.
It's great.
She interacts with the world in a completely
different way than the way we do.
Locking her up is the worst
possible thing you could do.
Thank you so much, Mr.
Washington.
Good luck.
It's not your fault, John.
This person...
they lied about everything.
But just because the lies are shocking
and they attract a lot of attention...
it doesn't necessarily
make them true.
It was very important for us to...
to check the facts and
to question the facts...
until it was evident
that I was innocent.
And once we've proven my innocence,
we went back to that proof...
over and over again, and looked
at it with a fresh set of eyes.
Because only then, were we able
to actually see the truth.
Are there any questions?
How does it feel to be designated?
That's a good question...
and I just want to thank
my constituency...
I just downloaded it.
Aren't they great? Better
than what you had before.
Hello?
Can you come over?
I need to see you, John.
Anna, look, I need to talk to...
Before it's too late!
Something terrible has
happened and I need to...
What?
Hello?
You have reached the
Greene's residence.
Please leave a message and we'll get
back to you as soon as we can.
Hello?
Anna?
John.
Hey!
Open the door!
John, there's someone in our house!
Shit!
Mom? Mom?
Hello?
Wh... emergency...
Hello, can you hear me?
Shit.
I don't want to die!
Hey! Hey! Open the goddamn door!
911, what's your emergency?
I'm at 1103 Bayside.
I have an intruder and
a serious assault.
Okay, that's right.
We already have multiple units
responding to that address, sir.
Anna!
Wait!
John.
Anna! You okay? You hurt?
Look, we're being followed...
but the police are here, you stay
with me you're gonna be safe. Okay?
I'm sorry.
What?
There's something over there!
Hey! Hey!
Over here!
Hey! Stop! Stop!
Hey! Somebody's broken into
the Greene's house!
Police!
I'm pretty su...
Stay where you are!
Stay right where you are!
Hands up, Mr. Washington!
You're suspected of
murder, Mr. Washington.
We found hundreds of pictures
featuring underage girls...
in your computer.
She set me up.
A 16 year-old girl.
Look. We know the parents were constantly
threatening to send the girl to an institution...
and that you... strongly
disagreed with that.
So the way I see it, you
got too close to the girl.
You drugged the parents, so
you could take her away...
but she refused to go and you end up doing
something you'd never think you were capable of.
The parents are okay?
Yeah... we found the mother's
sleeping pills in the kitchen, John.
And I'd be willing to bet that your fingerprints
are all over that prescription bottle.
We found a letter opener,
covered in blood...
in the forest, where you were.
I can explain every peace of
evidence you think you have.
We're carefully going through
the tapes of you chasing Anna.
Now obviously you disabled
a number of the cameras...
and then turned the power
off to cover your tracks.
I was locked inside the
surveillance room!
Recognize this?
Anna gave me that.
It's the key to the
surveillance room.
You panicked, needed an alibi...
so you damaged the interior of
the door, but you forgot...
that you had the key
in your pocket.
Do the right thing, John...
and tell me what you
did with the girl.
I went to the house,
I was looking for her.
And you got locked in
the surveillance room.
Exactly. And when I got out,
it was too late.
And there was blood on the floor in the
hallway, I followed the trail to the forest!
- And that's how you got the
blood on your shoes? - Yes.
By following the trail of blood from a
16 year-old... in a massive forest.
Yes, and... she came
out of nowhere.
She... she grabbed my hands, my
hands had blood on them.
She ran away.
And was this before or after
she called 911 on her cell...
screaming and crying that you were chasing
her through the house, trying to kill her?
There is plenty of
evidence to convict you.
There was someone else there.
You're gonna die in jail.
And coming back... now.
End of move, end of move!
Okay, that's it.
We visited all the necessary
memories together...
through every aspect of your
involvement in Anna's case.
I should have realized
what she was doing.
It's not your fault, John.
Anna was able to study our protocols
during your time with her...
and she eventually became strong enough
to control and manipulate the sessions.
She was even able to figure out that water
triggered the memories of your wife's suicide.
She needed you to be
responsible for her death.
If she just ran away, her parents
would just keep searching for her.
Did you find anything?
I'll submit our sessions
to the judge...
specifically highlighting the time you
were locked in the surveillance room...
and when you spoke to
her in the forest...
but as you know, our sessions don't
yet carry the same weight...
as eye witness testimony in court.
The only irrefutable evidence you could
have is proving Anna's still out there...
but... that's something
beyond my capabilities.
Mr. Lundgren?
I'm so sorry.
I don't know how she
made me believe her.
She had me completely fooled.
It's all good, John.
You've been under a lot
of pressure lately.
Thank you.
The judge is gonna consider
Peter's testimony for sure...
but since you both
work for Mindscape...
there are some legal issues we need
to get over and that'll take time.
I know.
Now... the sooner you get rid
of the house the better.
It won't take long before
the bail will be granted.
But don't worry, John,
you're not alone.
I'm gonna do everything in my power
to help you get clear of this.
And you just want to
send a single rose?
A single rose and...
this photograph.
Would you be so kind as to remove all
the thorns, before sending it over?
You can count on it, yeah.
The funny thing about memory...
is that it can't be fully trusted.
And yet, in the end, it's
the only truth we have.
And no matter how painful it is,
you gotta look at the truth...
because sometimes...
it's the only thing
that can save you.
It's the only thing...
that can set you free.
I just thought I'd...
try to come up so you could say no.
Come in.